I thought what we might want to do is
set up what we wanted well let me let me
indicate what I'd like to do and then
maybe we could all say would like to do
and then we could come to some consensus
agenda quickly I'm interested in
exploring and this is completely
self-serving in a lot of ways this
project that I'm on right now which is
the project of trying to understand
what's happening in terms of a lot of
our shared work in terms of you know
comparing it I think fruitfully to the
ancient meta secular technology of
dialectic and trying to put that into a
dialogue with what's going on and see if
it's possible to integrate the kind of
thing you do guy encircling the kind of
things you do Jordan in your talks where
you're pursuing coherence with people if
we can integrate that with you know
phyleus sophia for lack of a better term
so that we have something analogous to
the meta sacred technology of ancient
dialectic I've been trying to work out
both the cognitive science and the
phenomenological dimensions and try and
get in the coordinator at their meeting
sorting a lot of new research Sperber
stuff on the dialectical nature of the
biological nature of reasoning process
stuff on procedural metacognition
because I think it's deeply relevant for
example to what's going on in circling
and so I would I would like to and you
know and I've been exploring that with
with both you Jordan and you guys
individually and then you guys have also
been doing something I think at least
structurally analogous and then you know
and Chris is of course one of my
constant partners in crime in all and
all of these endeavors are trying to see
how people are responding to the meeting
crisis so that's what I would like to do
maybe everybody could take a moment to
you know check in and say what they
would like out of this and what also
might be a valuable to our you know our
respective audiences etc because we're
deciding to record this and then maybe
we can coordinate a consensual agenda so
I'll pass it to a Chris next okay
so what I think
it might be interesting to sort of
there's this particular strand this
particular I want to call it a method
but it's not quite a method but this
sort of these kinds of conversations
that are happening in the virtual space
are inflected with a particular kind of
Tilak orientation that that has setting
them apart from the normal discourses
that were used to seeing because we're
used to seeing discourses one in one of
a number of categories right we're used
to seeing discourse as as casual and
social or reduce to seeing it formalized
and in the sense of a more academic or
scholarly or intellectual conversations
we're accustomed to seeing things framed
in debate and obviously there's a
debates are inflected with competition
and so that creates a particular accent
in a particular way of relating to the
exercise and that's clearly not what's
going on here right this is what's going
on here aren't a series of debates and
even though their social entered and
they're genial and there's a certain
warmth to these conversations which is
an asset to them they're not quite that
either so there's some combination of a
more scholarly or a more intellectual
interface but but accented with the sort
of warm conviviality and and the fact
that then they're recorded and they're
publicized adds yet another dimension so
you and I were talking recently about
this John about how the the combination
of these different strands of
conversation these different methods of
dialogue in 2d logos maybe creates a
fertile ground for for symbolization for
something altogether new and something
that might actually be a host of
something that then can be can be
leveraged in all kinds of ways so maybe
to annotate what's the what exactly how
is this kind of diya logos different
from what we're accustomed to and then
what potential does that afford I like
that idea about symbol on that what's
happening right now is we're trying to
join together things that have
previously not been joined together and
that opens up a field for new
symbolization I think that's an
important point I just wanted to know
the next verse you pick Jordan please
I'm wondering if we're if we were all
actually oriented the same way spatially
in our visual field for me this was the
counter clockwise rotation does anybody
else have that yeah for me it's left to
right and it's linear I'm most left then
Chris is right and they needed to get to
the right of Chris and to the right of
you
so interest on it Wow so I thought I was
in the left so Kristin has to add that
to the equation which is we're also
we're also dealing with the reality of
the the complexification of dialogue
where each of our perspectives on the
relationships that are happening are at
least a little bit mysterious hmm so for
me this this feels a lot like a
continuing inquiry into the real
embodiment in the form of a distributed
cognition the mystery of a meta psycho
technology something along those lines
feels like that's what is pulling me
here we just kind of keeps ringing in my
in my consciousness as we continue in
this path so that's what I would say and
to me that sounds a lot like a variation
of what I've just heard before so maybe
some different things coming in a
different direction
mmm great I'm well the real reason why
I'm here is I I continually have
experiences with the three well I guess
four phases that I'm looking at where it
seems like we have a conversation which
the linguistic Luke called guy cannot
survive and I like that and and I want
to notice as it happens and when it
doesn't happen what are the patterns we
see connect all the things that you're
talking about because I think that
there's something one of the things that
brings us all together that you've all
kind of
mentioned is there's something there's
some kind of dialog like dialo goes that
goes on it seems to me one of the few
places in our times where people are
relatively still as as chris highlighted
available to to be touched right in ways
that go beyond all of their
representations and reorganised and so I
just think that there's something about
about wow how we dialogue about anything
but but but let that let the dialogue
and how it works and and how to how to
articulate it in a way that it's it's um
it's procedures so we can we can we can
bring it in and distribute it and make
it more available and have that more
more of those interactions be really
available in all the different
dimensions so I want to like talk about
that um and I also want to find
ourselves doing it mmm not doing it and
then noticing that and then asking what
was just happening mm-hmm that's very
good
Jordan and I talked about you know
constantly moving between head and Hara
you know the conceptual theoretical
space but also Rhian gauging deep in the
Hara right that embodied centeredness
and so yeah I think we should keep that
going maybe I could maybe I could start
if I'll just propose something as an
initial thing and maybe that would with
gel because it sounds like we are pretty
convergent and what we want to do I want
to pick up on what Jordan said because
the work on doing was sparked by his
invocation and the insight that he
provoked in me when you invoke the
notion of a meta sacred technology
psycho technology that in some sense
orchestrates and Shepherds vets and
generates and dispenses with obsolete
psycho technologies in some fashion that
coordinates to give us
access to the power of distributed
cognition and the collective
intelligence therein as something that
will guide us normatively and
practically in again the generation the
dispensing the organization
orchestration of psycho technologies for
addressing what I've called the meaning
crisis and so I want to I want to pick
up on on on that as an idea and one of
the things that I'm interested in is
because that was as what I see ancient
dialectic doing is dialectic is both
that kind of meta psycho technology
operating with the in distributed
cognition but it also reflects back it's
interjected back into individual
cognition and it becomes write a process
of them the you know the aspiration
towards the medic your estate of wisdom
so the the sort of ontological movements
right within the individual of
coordinate the access to distribute
cognition and so those are let me I'm
trying to sort of lay out what I know
I'm not claiming this exhaustive but
there's sort of an emergent phenomena
Lachie and and it's helpful because it's
a phonology that can be put into some
cognitive process in terms for me
so there's if you'll allow me there's a
horizontal dimension which is the
interpersonal which leads to the the
meta psycho technology in distributed
cognition and then dialectic also has
the metahuman those two are feeding each
other and then there's there seems to be
another dimension when we've already
alluded to in which we're constellation
between theory and Fiore aware shifting
between theorizing and then taking it
back in and seeing if it becomes
something that is contemplative Lee
available to us and viable to us right
and then there's one that Jordan and guy
have marked very clearly and repeatedly
and I think and this is a provocative I
mean in a sense of thought-provoking
thing there's this other dimension which
is every current conversation is a mesh
and right is profuse the constraining
presence I mean constraining in both
positive and negative sense you know
both limiting and affording the
constraining a presence of other
conversations that are right so that
well I think Jordan you called it at
won't put a meta conversation the meta
conversation that seems to be another
dimension and then there's some overall
dynamic dimension of how they constantly
well not that's too strong they have the
potential to like come into I'll use
your term year now Jordan a kind of
coherence whereby they are mutually
affording each other in a sort of
nonlinear fashion that has some
intelligible novelty as a constant
feature of it it's constantly having an
emergent disclosing aspect to it so
those are sort of the dimensions I'm
sort of seeing at work in what we're
doing and I'm just putting them out
there and asking now for some responses
so we can get some some you know get
some riffing going gets it some jazz or
the jonlizz down II mean based rap I
felt very much dropped into the groove
so a guy from from my perspective I felt
somewhere between 75 and 80 90 percent
of the time that there was a feeling of
flown us there that I could actually
kind of like feel myself drawn into the
space that was expressing itself through
John's voice and actually I popped into
a place of actually noticing it very
physically when he corrected himself on
the term constantly with regard to the
meta conversation because when he
corrected himself it brought my
attention to the fact that he himself
felt that something was off in the flow
and then I was like oh yes that's right
and so even deeper it was actually
brought deeper into a feeling of
residence and synchrony because I could
actually sense where the where the flow
was and where the languaging had been
off so I I was as you were talking John
I was thinking also of of yeah you
talked about figuratively the relation
between the head and the heart
that seemed to be foraging in these
conversations and how there's something
about the training of the relational
training that happens inter subjectively
what and you might say horizontally
right there's some there's a it's almost
like there's sort of a pedagogical
function to the inter subjective
relation that then manages to espouse
verticality right I think of the
metaphor like two people working
face-to-face with one another and
they're cooperative in a particular
activity and then as they cooperate in a
particular activity the ground beneath
them deepens as a consequence almost
incidentally so that there is sort of a
I guess so that the to use the term that
you adapted from our glue has sort of
the reciprocal widening you know that
happens between persons ends up becoming
accepted into an ontological reciprocal
way right then they happen they happen
they happen they happen simultaneously
um and so and so then if that's true or
if something analogous to that is true
it makes sense of the fact that these
social interactions seem to bear witness
to something of a higher order a
presence to the interaction seems to
possess the interaction because it's
accessing something perhaps ontological
II that's not it's something emergent
ontological II that's not reducible to
any one of the participants nor even the
conversation itself that there's a meta
practice at work no that's really good I
like those two threads so there's one
which Jordans Jordans I think very
important point about the stents like
the Daath right of this and then what
you're pointing to is there's it was
kind of like on a bucket gone off oh the
off the doth is the an ancient word for
sort of faith
it means being coupled in coupled to a
system such that your transformation
discloses to you how the course of
events is going is undergoing
transformation and you you can follow
the flow and then you can sense when
you're off course and trespassing and
then you need to
back on target and stuff like that it's
sort of a biblical notion I was using
that because you know it because what
Joyce is pointing to is there's a
there's there's there's there very much
that sense and yet it has a normative
guidance to it and then for me that
leaps I think I get a sense I don't know
how to articulate it but I think you get
a sense that it links to what Chris is
talking about because this the this
deducing the seduction adduction of this
emergent thing seems to be a place that
well to use your words call it calls to
us that it has that kind of normativity
the adduction like it's like is it's
like if things are getting adduced from
us we feel something has emerged that
it's also drawing us the the drawing
forth from us in education is precisely
the sense of something beyond us drawing
us along I'm trying to tie the education
that you're talking about Chris to the
sense that Jordan was was mentioning yes
and and I think it is that and I think
this is this is drawn from perhaps from
Jordan and I your your conversation
which I saw or one of your conversations
which I saw recently about the idea that
but whatever is drawing us forth is also
speaking us that we are being spoken by
and one of one of you said that wasn't
me but this idea of vocality which
harkens to the logo strike the meaning
of locality as being gathered by it
being spoken by it I think is
wonderfully resonant both of those being
gathered to belong together but also
being spoken like intelligibility
emerging from us and in us it's it's
almost like as we are transformed we are
informed in that that becomes the basis
for the information that feeds into our
intelligibility but but Jordan is I
think he wants to say something well the
only thing that I would like to say
right now is just to notice the feeling
of for me at least sacredness began to
build in the past few moments yeah and
to be very careful with the presence
that is disclosing itself among us given
that well that is the right way to
relate to that
I think that's right I like the
invocation of that term also because
that's something that you know Jordan
and and and and guy
well also Chris but Jordan and I we've
been talking a lot about the religion
it's not a religion and the the chance
that all of this meta conversation might
be linked to I don't know what word to
use here but something like a new
appreciation I'm trying to pick up on
many senses of the word appreciation a
new appreciation of sacredness and it
seems like I'm really glad that you said
said said that Jordan cuz it yeah okay I
was about to say that and I think that
sacredness that we can we can find
ourselves inside of that there's
something about there's something for me
about with Spence in the way and this is
speaking to this this implicit thing
that's going on that's at that it almost
requires us not to be aware of it and
then find ourselves in it having it
already had begun it's like I like you
know all the many times I was like doing
mushrooms with my friends all night long
and then at some point somebody looks
over this said hey look the dawn but the
there is this experience of insight that
we had that it was already dawn before
we recognizes so part of the recognition
was the recognition that we hadn't
noticed that it was already dawn that
sense of that that sense of something as
we're dialoguing this necessary
concealment of of that that horizon is
peeking up and then there's that moment
of already right of all readiness that
reveals the ground that we were standing
on this kind of sense that the ground in
the horizon that there's this kind of
moment of reveal unrevealed that is
sucked that that that seems
characteristic or can be disclosed that
we then I think call something like
sacred
I sorry I love I love the use of the
word dawning guy I think because it both
it evokes the sort of the the the lumen
ating metaphor but also the coming into
being that something is comes into being
by realization and that our realization
of the presence is also it's coming into
being at the to and coupled and dawning
is such a beautiful turn because it it
speaks both of those together I just I
just really I love that yeah I loved it
I love your use of that the dawning also
indicates that something that there's
arrives and from which the dawning thing
has come right there's also a sense of
right the dawning points to that from
which right that the darkness from which
it will always come right because it's
cut that comes from over the horizon and
I like that aspect of the idea of
dawning to I so I mean this is a theme
like III now it's at the beginning I was
gonna this was gonna be one of the
things I did this is a theme in the
ancient practice of dialectic I mean and
the metaphor that Plato used that he
used it and it's it's a difficult
metaphor given our current sort of
cultural political climate but the
metaphor is so apt because of all the
things he evokes he says we we always
are we always have to be seduced into
philosophy right and this picks up on
agnes color it's notions of aspiration
right we if if we if we if we made it I
mean this sounds simplistic but if we
make it it's not sacred I mean we have
to people you have to feel ourselves
drawn into it and it has to have it has
to have like something analogous to
agency they like what you're talking
about guy it has this it has its own
internal grammar if you let me that
metaphor that is running before us but
and that makes it possible for us that
we have to have kind of a reverence and
respect to I I think I think that's I I
agree with that and like
resonates a reason why I like the
seduction metaphor for all of its
troubling associations aside is it
brings in right again because think
about this love is that way to write
love draws you but if you make it it's
not love right and if somebody just if
you're just receiving it it's not love
there's something this is what what I'm
struggling and you guys have all seen it
I'm struggling to really try and develop
this platonic notion of participation
right it's neither if we we make it it's
not sacred and if we try to make love
it's not love sorry you know what I mean
we can make love in another sense but if
it's something we try to construct in an
authorial fashion it's not love mm-hmm
and if and if we are if we're just
receiving passively that's not either
either and the reason why this matters
is because I know because I know Jordan
talks a lot about love and I also this
brings up on one of the Platonic virtues
which is saw Fersen right so this is
this is we have no good word for
translating it it's often translated as
temperament temperance or ma our
moderate modesty or moderation none of
the words are good right it means a kind
of self-control but it's the kind of
self-control that we find ourselves in
rather it it's not like in credit gratia
is you know I want to do that thing but
I'm not gonna do it and I hold myself
back I make myself not do it but soft
resan is I could do that I don't want to
but I'm naturally tempted to do they're
good I find myself loving the good
rather than having to resist the evil
and so I the reason I'm on about this
right now is because that seems to me to
be a point where sort of platonism and
Christianity touched and then the notion
of the church as a gathering and
platonic dialectic as a gathering the
logos and Christianity the logos now you
see I'm fun I'm flinging things out here
because I I can sense them you know
drawing towards each other and that's
well that's why I'm here I want to bring
this into discussion I want to see you
know what we can do with these potential
connections that's the ellipse that's da
logos
John would you say the the Greek word
again and if we didn't spell it in the
Greek letters I don't know if I could
spell it in the Greek letters I haven't
done my ancient Greek in a bit it's
softer son the word son saw for a son
yeah so s oh that the our script would
be SOP H ro sy or su because ha the
thing in Greek is between the two UN and
look at so Y or you and II and for some
yeah it's one of the four cardinal
virtues with wisdom courage and justice
and it's one of you don't talk very much
about in our society but because of its
connections to love and logos and
ecclesia and dialectic it seems to me
like it might be the virtue that senses
the normativity that we're talking about
here that's what I'm proposing mm-hmm
that this sounds very much like it's a
nice way of describing how I felt before
I spoke a moment ago there was there was
an awareness of a like a path to pass me
one path had a path that was moving too
fast so he muddying the waters or
grasping and the other path is a path
that had more respect and therefore the
more available to reveal some and that
the the sensing of rightness like the
real like listening to where rightness
was callin and which direction had that
feeling of being called up and into
oriented towards the path of we need to
be very careful of protecting the
sacredness at the moment mmm so frisson
okay right and so Plato dedicates a
dialogue to it in fact the comedies
where it's all about saw Fersen and it's
interesting because it's a dialogue
that's also considered to be where he
talks a lot about his notion of
rationality and also one of the clearest
exemplification of Socratic and Linkous
all those three were circling very
tightly together in that in that
particular dialogue
Jordan when you made that distinction in
that felt sense of there's something
sacred and there's a case and you could
feel the two and be aware of that you
were feeling the two lack of a better
way of putting this
what was this sense organ you were
mm-hmm you were eating different
excellent excellent question it felt
like from the top of my throat to about
six inches below my belly button and my
front so you'd say my upper torso thymos
the thymus yes yeah and I and I noticed
as you say that that there's like a
couple of other examples was a feeling
of that sort the one that just came to
me was actually as a child actually
being learning how to be in relationship
with an animal like a mostly like a cat
mm-hmm
or there's a sensing of the real sensing
of the sensitivity at the moment of how
to actually put yourself in a place
where you're creating in an invitation
and very very very much has to actually
be a real invitation it can't be a fake
invitation I'm saying the difference
yeah and really just listening to what
is calling for itself in the other
something like that this beautiful city
so this reminds me of what you just said
reminds me of a distinction that you I
think I think you made this guy this
distinction of vulnerability versus
exposure in one of in one of these
dialogues and how and I remember
thinking that and thinking of hearing
that I'm thinking that it was such a it
was such a well articulated distinction
because to me it actually tracks it
tracks the modal difference between
having and being right because exposure
is that something has been laid that
that something has been involuntarily
stripped from you that you've been
somehow dispossessed and are at a loss
and are in danger and vulnerability
obviously is volitional and that that's
the difference so there's something
about the sort of volitional nature of
being vulnerable that allows the allows
that allows the
tuning to rhythm I think that you're
describing Jordan that you have and it
has to do with that listening to
harkening that that you need to that you
need to sort of that that there's that
there's a necessary kind of deportment
of vulnerability required to be able to
synchronize and tune with someone else
and then to synchronize in tune more
broadly in a more cosmic way if I can
use that term and and and that one way
of perhaps understanding the function of
this do logos is as a training in
vulnerability not just social
vulnerability but also a kind of
existential and phenomenological
vulnerability that then seeds to the
reference that you're describing hmm
there's a lot I noticed I noticed
hums happening yeah that was good in
this something I just wanted little
pieces I'm just that are coming speaking
to me is there's something about there's
something about listening or hearing
that I'm hearing that sense of because
I've noticed that I look into my own
life okay so there's that quality that
you're talking about um where what are
those things that if I to me what which
which transcendence what beyond the
horizon if I tuned into it will afford
all these capacities coming forward
right in my character and draw in
another else and then create these
things right when is what is it okay I
guess it's like what sense organ maybe
literally and metaphorically do I use to
detect that particular transcendence
right and then notice what's off and on
in that kind of way and I think it's I
think hearing is what's really speaking
to me because
there's a way in which seeing right
seeing has his quality as it ended its
own kind of temporal dimension to it
where it's like you see surface of
things right therefore you end up
extinct in when you're in a lot of
seeing metaphor you end up explaining a
lot right because you're only seeing the
surfaces so it draws a certain kind of
temporality to it
you can also kind of get the sense of
like the newtonian you very thing that
you think you can get you can see the
world as like things that still and then
they move and other things move and you
get this kind of you can you can draw
out Newton and all of its wonders
but then there's listening which is
listening has this quality as far as I
can tell it's like one is like if I I
look at the table right I have to kind
of explain what's going on internally
but if I hear the table there's a way
that the that I it discloses is that
it's imperii Ora tea right there's
something about sound right that that
and and then we look at like well what
is you know dialogue like there's if we
did if we couldn't speak to each other
and we were just standing here looking
at each other like it'd be a completely
different experience but there's this
thing about that them through the medium
of sound and hearing that seems to
reveal interior tea a Vulcan Aurora tea
and use the organ of interior tea right
or it to be revealed the other thing
about hearing which is really
interesting when you think about it
that's different than seeing it's an
acoustical space is it a certain sense
infinitely unfillable like like we're
we're visual space I can kind of fill it
up right there's a finite but like
acoustical space I think you can you can
get it is like deeply silent or you can
like you can get it infinitely loud
there's something about it that
as in a an infinity about it like a
horizon in which it can it can resonate
so many different things at once so I'm
just kind of what I'm a momzilla trance
well that's the one thing I wanted to
pick up on though the last thing you
said she sound has the capacity for kind
of resonance that that's that vision
doesn't have and it and it's interesting
that because the Hebrew God is invisible
they owe the overwhelming sense that is
invoked for coming into relationship to
him as here it mark and hearken hearken
Hartman or taste Parkin and taste
because those are ones that describe
resonance because it you know the
relationship is a covenantal
relationship which is not a contract we
misunderstand a covenant as a contract
because a covenant is supposed to be a
relationship of resonance of reciprocal
opening not just agreement and so I
think hearing is confidential in in the
way right in which sight isn't like I
think you're right sight moves us
towards a more of an appropriation our
relationship whereas hearing if I'm
getting you right because of its
capacity for resonance and covenants
puts us into that kind of reciprocal
relationship and one thing that
resonance I think it actually does to
John is it seems to be evocative of the
other senses a sound can evoke a smell a
sound can evoke something a sound evokes
tactility in the way that sight doesn't
and I think that's all I think that's
all folded into that resonance is that
capacity to be so so is it is the
capacity to fan out those communications
we could embody aspects of sound we
could we could we literally
participatory
we have we embody in our body in our
thigh muscle ism and pit pacing and lots
of things it's yeah on the horizon
right I can Jenna something and not know
what I'm not in there's a link between
if I hear something I don't know what it
my wife is like this like crazy she
hears a sound you know what it's like
every stop you just kind of link between
hearing and knowing and that there's an
availability that hearing is has the
capacity to be hear what it doesn't when
it doesn't know right right right right
so there's there's a kind of
vulnerability in the center of hearing
yeah the implication of hearing has the
notion of the relationship between the
silence and the sound and notice the
metaphorical connection to the rising of
the Sun right when we know that the
sound is followed by silence is followed
by sound and that's how we understand
that when the Sun goes away we have a
feeling that it comes back and there's
rhythms in nature that are happening all
the time mm-hmm and then we are always
going to be open to the possibility of
what comes next cuz they have a feeling
that next this is a thing that's good
recently his book bearing witness to
epiphany talks about the musicality of
intelligibility there the way you just
talked about Jordan that there's these
rhythms that we pick up on and they're
there and they're constantly playing
between determination and what's
indeterminate like you said God and and
so there's there's something interesting
there Jordan though because that that
that brings me back to dog because what
you're talking about is a kind of trust
which isn't the same thing as like you
know seeing that it is the case but it
is a sense of you know again resonance
you know I've been trained to trust it's
because that's this that notion is
circling around again that one of the
differences for me between vulnerability
and exposure is that vulnerability for
me and that this is how I've expressive
when I sense reciprocal covenant show of
all nur ability with somebody that
engenders trust in me which is not the
same thing as me knowing now I've got
Jordan I've got him I know what he's
gonna do that's not what Trust is Trust
is not I see what he's going to do trust
is right I have this embodied sense were
coupled together and he's vulnerable
like me we are Co humanized to get
and that's why untrusting right that
that covenant relation I figure as much
of much of what we mean by faith would
you see that again the Covenant shal Co
respiration that John is just describing
and and and Jordans sort of invocation
of the rhythm of that Co respiration
it's reliable rhythmic nature and our
connection to that reliable rhythmic
nature the way it allows us to model Co
model mutual model I guess you as you
would say John yes I think much of what
we mean by faith yeah it's the it's the
sense that the mutual modeling has taken
taken present its present and the thing
I want to say about the reliability I
think that's the right term but I I'm
cautious and I wanted to do what Jordan
said always respect the sacredness here
the reliability is not that like I said
you can see all the implications
it's a reliability that a this sounds
like a Zen Cohen it's a reliability that
expects novelty that expends alive
yes exactly yeah I'm wondering about
that that expects it's a reliability
that expects novelty but it also sounds
like what created its reliability was in
a certain sense its relationship to
novelty yeah I think it's the sense that
there's a like the coupling gives an
additive 'ti to novelty that you you
have a sense of now embodying that's how
it feels to me I feel like when I'm
talking to you guys or even when I'm
talking to somebody who I might have
more significant theoretical differences
with I use the example of Paul there to
click and we should invoke Paul in this
conversation anyways um because he's
present in a sense and you know he and I
disagree about quite a bit or or or
Jordan your conversation with Jonathan
Perot I think also speaks to this right
the two of you I sense because I've
talked to both of you at some point the
more philosophical topics you have some
significant philosophical degree
disagreements about some things but
nevertheless there was genuine resonance
in there and I sensed that you know
again you were being equally vulnerable
and there was there was a growing sense
of trust between you because I could
since the flow of the conversation
taking shape and that's exactly it
and it's and it's precise because it
takes shape belong to me
that I have a trust in it that sounds so
simplistic but that's part of what's
going on well there's this feeling that
I've had my wife and I have begun
playing instruments together with our
one one-year-old Methodists who have a
particular history of musicality so
we're actually just exploring that all
together and one of the things that I've
definitely noticed is that there's a
period of time let's say we both have
drums where something's not there
there's a lack of something hmm and then
there's a moment and as guy will remind
us it is a moment that we always notice
after it has already been there where
there's a sensing of there being a
dropping into a groove a sensing if
there's something is now holding us that
is real and it creates a context of this
notion of daf this notion of faith this
notion of trust and as you say John
precisely the aliveness of us is that
many many things can happen that are
totally unexpected unanticipated but
they're alright because they're held in
the groove and there's something about
not just alright but actually they're
delightful they open things up and so
there's a move like there's a rhythm and
the rhythm and also in the pods and if
somehow we all kind of knew hold to hold
the pause and the silence and silence
and silence and then when the note drops
back in it's a feeling of boom we're
back there but the groove was actually
holding the whole space and that seems
to happen right there seems to happen in
the conversation where there's a time
when we're trying to figure out how to
actually bring this thing into the
groove in the groove lands and we can
feel the invitation of the possibility
and each thing is now invited into a
higher degree of novelty and higher
degree of creativity because it's held
in a container where that possibility is
well the word I would use is joyful mmm
yeah I like joyful mm-hmm like joyful
and use notice this ayat like we stopped
talking with that moment what is this
moment press I'm appreciating for the
appreciation or appreciating the joy I
like both a great understanding and
gratitude and thank God I'm alive and
I'm glad to be here and guys are great
that's all what's yeah
yeah I appreciate
and comes to my my - in both senses of
appreciation right the gratitude part of
appreciation and the deepening is the
deepening and agog sense of appreciation
yes yes yes yeah and a gaga yeah right
you know this is what a note that that
stuff yeah but you invoke that but I got
to put those move clearly together thank
you Chris there's a deeper kid there's a
deep connection between via logos and an
agog a right there's something because
the the moving up the ontological levels
is also making use of the horizontal
thing but but it's transposed onto the
world that's very good that's very good
okay I would say I only take about that
I want to say I want to settle with that
one for a moment like I'm still right at
your forehead can you would you say that
would you say that again just that so so
I was talking about these two dimensions
at the Ilocos right the horizontal the
interpersonal right and then the for
lack of a better one deontological but
then right and but the an agog aid the
reciprocal opening which is what moves
you up the ontological levels also
invokes although the relationship is
with the world right in voc's something
like the covenantal resonance with the
world because right what's happening is
the sukkah is getting organized that
allows me to see more deeply into the
world and then the world can speak more
deeply to me I can harken better to it
that transforms me I seem right and then
you get something analogous to what
happens in conversation happening in
Aragog a and so there is a bridge
between the interpersonal communication
and the ontological right the
ontological movement in the notion of an
acog a so there's a deep connection I
think well at least in Plato between
dear logos and an agog a
and then dialectic well yes very much of
course
yeah it's dialectic how you bet what's
the distinction dialectic how's that
different so well here you please John
no no you go ahead I think and I'm
playing around with these terms and I'm
playing with all of you in a sense of
you know appreciative serious play about
which how are these terms gonna fall out
for us but for the dialectic for Plato
with something above and beyond just
dialogue because the eye electic meant
the coordination of all these dimensions
that I've talked about together so
there's a sense of which part of the
time when you were practicing dialectic
you would be by yourself in a non
linguistic the OREA practicing something
like a contemplative and a gog a and but
that was also somehow like I said it's
interwove in with what we're doing now
you know a back and forth conversation
and so dialectic was typically the more
that the term that the term the term
Plato used for what I would call the
psycho technology that was coordinating
all of these together
that's why Hegel took up the term
dialectic I think he changed it
fundamentally from the Platonic context
but that's why he took up the notion of
dialectic rather than dialogue formation
that that that just really run out to me
that word of this this that's what seems
like it feels like in listening so in
listening to everybody speak and all the
different threads that are Co hearing
and coming in and coming apart and and
then being at the center of John's head
which I would recommend when I'm
participating in that way it's I am I
feel like I've become a better
coordinator I'm coordinating things this
kind of right at the this is the
vulnerability part of of or even right
now I'm just right at the edge of the
thought and I could fall over right but
there's a there's something I'm
listening to and I'm tuning into I'm
looking at all of your faces
you're handing back and forth that you
know what how does poor coordination
come into play with this because it
whatever it is it feels like that's what
I'm doing in what it takes to listen and
engage and participate on this
oh I think there's a there's a
phenomenological and ACOG sigh I'll
start briefly because I'd like to hear
what Jordan says because guy ice a--they
both you and Jordan that being masters
of what you've just put your finger on I
think and I mean this with a lot of you
know respect I think you'd the two of
you one of the things that I deeply
value and appreciate is exactly that I'm
not trying to say that's the only thing
but one of the things that often stands
out to me and I'll stand back and I'll
go wow that would like something like
what you just articulated that
coordination phenomenologically I want
to propose one aspect of it that the
coordination seems to me that there's a
sense in which that the trusting is
becoming embodied we're trusting that
part of us that's participating in the
Daath hmm and so that there's a trust
like when I'm when I'm sparring or doing
the Tai Chi there's that sense the
coordination I have to trust in in that
participation in the Daath speaking as a
kasnia scientist which is a different
thing and so I want to be careful here
about keeping the balance between theory
and furia but you know what we're
talking about I think a kind of
exaptation
we're taking the cerebellum which
functions in the literal sensory motor
coordination and we now we now have the
increasing evidence of this that it gets
exacted to coordinate any complex set of
contingencies that it's encountered not
just sensory motor contingencies so what
we're doing and this is why you have
practices like Tai Chi Chuan the idea is
you put your system through sensory
motor challenge but you do it in such a
ritualized and I'm using that term
deliberately such a ritualized context
that it affords exacting the cerebellum
to trace you know complex contingencies
in your environment complex
contingencies in in your cognition
complex contingencies in your
communication and I think so and I think
those two go together because it when I
can trust in the participation I sort of
sink into my embodiment and I think that
helps trigger the excitation of the
cerebellum function and that's that's
how I would answer that but but like I
said I want to
I want to hear what Jordan and guide you
have to say because you guys like you
have an artistry about this and and I
want you to speak I want you to speak it
I wish I had magic here I just want to
derive what I want like I want to know
if what I said sings to your
phenomenology but obviously there's a
skillfulness that i want to understand
better as well
so now it made sense well it's neutral
it's a tricky business yeah that was not
that was non-trivial there's a whole
bunch of different things that were
being going on there and the the feeling
of trying to bring the teas in tune the
threads of indras net another thing to
actually play music and harmonies is not
trivial I think that's what is the any
query is that feeling of feeling I think
actually sense within yourself the
where's the word that you used well sets
of thin yourself the cerebellum doing
it's busy work trying to actually bring
all of these diverse capacities for
perceiving and expressing into their
sensitivity and listening or to what is
being you know what's coming and
noticing like where's that landing in me
and how do I actually shift that landing
and me and how do I bring these complex
pieces of me into alignment with each
other so that I'm the resonance is
getting louder and louder I'm listening
listening and then the signal pops very
clear and then the instrument of me that
can then actually bring it back out with
some clarity and fidelity as the the
thing that I was hearing and then that
was actually endeavoring to then do it
because I'd like to try to do it in the
process of actually even expressing it
which was not easy
hahaha well you just did it um but
there's a thing you do Jordan that I
guess if you allow me you speak
metaphorically
you'll pause and then you'll do
something you know the only thing that I
find analogous my own experience is
something like mindfulness or meditation
but you pause and I sense you you're
here's I'm gonna use my metaphors I
sense like your taste in your mind and
your tasting your mind and you're seeing
what it is portending do you know you
know the kind of events I thought yo go
yeah and I'm not mocking you you
understand and and then there's you're
you're trying to sense the the portents
of your mind and and it's like the omens
or or you know what I mean like I want
to what is happening in those moments
for you
not easy to explain yeah no no and
everybody thank you mister things are
happening though lots and lots of things
many many many things and what I notice
is that as yet as I get older I have
more ability to be in relationship with
the things that are happening I'll give
an example yes please I can't remember
exactly when this happened it was some
period of time ago maybe on the order of
about 12 minutes ago and I think it was
something well actually I'll do it an
earlier one so much earlier in the
conversation Chris very mentioned this
experience of the deepening of the
ground beneath you hmm
and remember he's in the process of
expressing something that is very very
complex and that's the language that he
used those are the words that fell out
of his mouth and to our ears and when he
said that I actually felt the ground
beneath me drop like not a little bit a
lot I actually felt a sense of of what's
that called
dizziness like a sense of like my
stomach actually actually vertigo and I
felt the vertigo landed in landed so
hard on my body of a whoa my god that is
there's something about that poetry that
was extremely powerful and then later
something that guy said I actually felt
misses I thought that was really
interesting I felt the sensation that I
learned about in the context of actually
what are they called son scars I think
is the language the word for it which I
actually felt physically something in my
chest coming up up my throat and
actually wanted to be breathed out of my
mouth but some part of me that was
almost like a piece of me that had
looked literally a piece of me was
liberated and healed in the experience
of that and so the physical physical
sensation of it as a physical sensation
as I had that physical sensation in
periods of my life and it was named
samskaara and I also was able to have
that old that experience happened enough
times to be in relationship with the
first person I am not downloading a
notion of what it is but just living it
and noticing it then the meaningfulness
of it when Nix when I experienced when I
feeI says something I'm like whoa okay
I've had this before that's interesting
becomes a thing that's part of the story
I'm the part of the
experiences I'm having and then as you
say this like part of me bins begins to
notice that but it notices it in the
context of all the other things that are
happening I had ever happened in my
entire experience and all the
conversations I've ever had and there's
something that happens with us like a
point where there's a way to kind of
allow that to settle and settle and
settle and listen and listen as you say
guy like listening with this broader you
know just this extended eardrum this
broad broad tympanum that's this
diaphanous and and multi-dimensional
listening out and then something is so
hard to explain it's like a this is good
though keep going keep going
ah it's like a um if I almost want to do
a Fourier transform on some sort of
super high dimensional signal that's
happening both temporally like these
silences and rhythms and also happening
in real time with multiple different
embedded overtones and there's something
about a wholeness too though that's the
thing it's it's quite diverse there's
lots and lots of different things but
there's a wholeness to it it's like a
lot of different things that have a
wholeness and that wholeness pops and
then I have some experience like the a
sensing of a wholeness that is
multimodal and not obviously connected
but you can listen and listen listen and
notice like like the eyes and the ears
and the sound imitation all the
experience is also like that's it that's
the thing and they're all connected so
that was great I'm glad we recorded that
that was great
Thank You Jordan that was fantastic
there's a way where I I really
appreciated you walking inside of that
and as you were describing the what you
were describing you were you were
simultaneously doing the thing that you
were describing in describing in thing
about that fractal Auto go
I think Taylor yeah there's and I I'm
I'm the question I'm I can hear like is
it seems that what calls the particular
thing
in particular holes interview that you
know to describe as relevant and not the
corner on the wall there's a there's
something that there's something it
feels like you are always a little bit
behind that thing that is as you're
describing it you're also trying to
describe why that's relevant as you're
finding it out there's a there's that
quality of it
but I'm sure is I'm wondering about and
this I think really is pertinent to the
whole conversation which is when is
what's beckoning you to even start doing
that like what is the thing that I'm
imagining it's something transcendent
I'm getting the sense of like the you
know the Heidi Aryan sense of ecstatic
time or or how the future calls
in its I get this sense if I were to put
it like this it's like it's almost like
the future is calling forth something
that my current representations can't
hold or may go away therefore I've
retained it in such a way that I start
to that that makes me think of again
Keller's notion that in aspiration
although I'm causing my future self my
future self is normatively calling me so
although I'm the I'm gonna do the things
that are gonna cause that future self so
there's no teleology that future self is
nevertheless has a normative authority
over me and it's calling me so what I am
just wondering is if does it does it
happen that the world if you'll allow me
to stretch this into an analogy does the
world have a future self that we have to
cause to be but nevertheless is
normatively calling us forward we're
aspiring towards that world and right
and it and it's inspiring us when I take
inspiration to be an insight that
affords an aspiration I call that self
brienne what that's on Brienne my wife
[Laughter]
yes no hold on no oh yeah yeah okay
let's go yeah yeah I did I can I've had
this experience I've mentioned just to
Vanessa several times like I sometimes
refer to her as my own my unconscious
more I am not actually even able to be
aware of myself or what's happening in
that she is in relationship with me our
relationship was off I don't even know
what's going on because that realize how
much of that and so what you just named
there guy I think is actually for real
like yes yes the sense organ that
invites us into the future she has a
name
yeah that's again that I I find the same
thing with Sara and that brings back
again too you know this is again that's
a platonic notion diet EEMA ultimately
was the one that led socrates
and that right and again there's the
seduction metaphor evoking that there's
some arrows is working all of this in
some powerful ways i don't yeah i agree
with jordan guy i don't i i think that
was a very fortuitous very fortuitous
thing you just did their naming you
naming your partner she's your wife
sorry I'm naming your wife and and you
Jordan also doing that I find the same
thing we saw at that same that same
thing so what did I and that of course
is I mean to speak is about you know
scientists again you know that the the
you know the mutually accelerating
disclosure is how you fall in love with
somebody they're mutually accelerate
that's the work the errands work right
the mutually accelerating disclosure so
I get more and more vulnerable than you
reciprocate that's how you can follow
along as we saw above and beyond just
wanting that sex with them right what
are like falling in love with them is
mutually accelerating disclosure so does
that mean so so this is just sort of
just this is a I don't know this is
weird juxtaposition does that mean that
there's a vulnerability to the world as
well hey this is I just want to say the
perceptual shift I just got on that was
made me turn around
[Laughter]
this is one uh so does that mean that
there's a vulnerability to the world
mm-hmm
I mean there are mythological frameworks
in which there if you'll allow me to use
these mythologically and not in sort of
any biological sense in which you know
the sacred is not only masculine but
also feminine not only yang but also
again right which brings in a fertility
that's the womb like equality yes
exactly
hmm both yes the womb like quality and
the fertility the source of creation mmm
and the he they keep her word for
compassion literally means to be like a
womb right which is I think in some ways
a better way of understanding perhaps
even more reflexively than the sort of
partner to partner relationship that the
three of you are describing but it's a
better way to conceive of oneself as
that having that womb like property
because then your your commitments your
covenants your inward covenants aren't
to a product but to the but to the proof
to the processional crafting the
processional birthing it's a credit if
with midwifery is to respect that womb
wound as a result yeah of course of
course um and and I and there's a way in
which that the practice of that the
practice of that midwifery when it
becomes when it becomes reflective can I
think afford access to afford connection
to one's okay I mean it can afford
access to the unthinkable in ways that
the unthinkable is not otherwise
accessible so when you were saying about
having a self that subsists ahead of you
that seems to draw you forth and
I think one thing that I've noticed just
of myself which is interesting is that
reflecting on the process of maturity is
being able to notice when the current
state of your relation with others and
with the world is completely super Sesa
v' to what was possible for yourself ten
years ago right being able to look back
and think well Who I am now the relation
to the way I've figured my life or the
way that my life has figured me in
relation is such that ten years ago I
could not have conceived it and being
able to then and then and then in
interior izing that realization into a
dialectic I think allows us to cast that
pattern forward to being able to in that
if if if the present and I'm speaking
horizontally but there's a way of course
in which this is vertical to that it
opens to the verticality but if my
present is unthinkable to my past and my
future is unthinkable to my present
right right and that that imagination
that that affords that rip that that
reflection affords then avails this
tension between the sort of the the self
that that death draws forth ahead of me
so I mean what soul on track I'm trying
to think of this so are you I want to
make sure I'm understanding here are you
saying the way I come to appreciate the
real possibility of others and that's
and that's and that is disclosed to me
in their vulnerability there's a sense
of which I have to come to appreciate
the real possibility of the world and
when that discloses itself to me that's
something like the world's former
ability is that what you're saying cuz
that's what I'm hearing from that yeah I
think so yeah that's good I like that
that's very good I like that
to clap my hands I like that that's
really good they just want to highlight
is the experience of money so when you
asked that question I literally spun
around and I was just like and I watched
myself
attempt to answer it was so obvious that
I had to go wider and wider and wider
and a certain point it was almost like
my vision would always happen to touch
himself like in this way that you do
this it's like you're somehow there's
this way that you you inner you inner
you inner weave like deep technical
terms in this I don't know this I though
poetry that's just so prosaic it's a
it's a Here I am the room did you start
weaving and marrying me to it or
something like that was it was the
experience of reference I thought um but
then that the thing about about
vulnerability which is really
interesting and this kind of starts to I
like the thing that you said about time
how the present is the UH the future is
the unthinkable to the present well what
do you know it's interesting if you
think about being vulnerable what that
means an intimacy like and if we say
well of all the things that are going
through my mind what are those things
that if I say them will will will open
the possibility of intimacy in it I
think what they are at least in Kirk
personal intimacy I think what they are
is those things that if I say them in in
I and I don't have the experience of
being understood or accepted I will feel
pain but what's interesting is that
there's a distinction that we talk about
in in different places that we come from
in communicational encircling and we
kind of draw this contrast between what
is it to speak with the intention right
and what is it in what's the opposite of
that and it and what we say is that like
well when you're not speaking with the
intention to relate in other words
to open towards intimacy then you could
say them having them having more of the
intention to control meaning I'm saying
what I'm saying I'm saying on the way
that I'm saying so is to that button so
that the future after I get done talking
is not anonymous to me right it's like
it's not that quality oh right but
there's something about intimacy that
agree that you're like you really are
saying the truth in whatever that is for
you is to the degree that when you get
done saying it you're now you have no
idea what's gonna happen next
and that experience is the first breath
of intimacy so there's just kind of
making this link to the vulnerability
world right thank you for that guy
that's beautiful I love this idea of
that this process D anonymizes the world
that's Jordan really liked it too so so
like you're kind of a bowing the world
without necessarily personifying the
world and that's a way again of you know
get entering into you a kind of
sacredness then which explains how then
the social relation becomes becomes
transmuted into the existential and
ontological relation that the and I
though dynamic becomes the the becomes
the means of relating to the world
there's definitely some deep conceptual
glue here yeah putting this is from
putting sticking things together for me
that was a really good point guy that
was really good take take the
implications you could lose that
together with what Chris said earlier in
terms of your the intelligibility of
your future self to your present self or
your presence up to your past self and
thinking about that in the context of
the the choice Rika's can actually
presented it as a choice intent and so
we can even say that to the degree to
which I make choices such that my
present self is in fact extremely
intelligible to my past self
that I have in fact not actually been
living in a particular way so there's
actually a very interesting that I shall
live such that my future self is
incomprehensible to my present self
becomes an aesthetic ethic invitation oh
that's very good
totally live into the moment that my
future self is so far that's very good
that's very good that's it's interesting
because that's I think what you just did
Jordan is you did something analogous to
the divine double that plays such a
crucial role in the neo platonic
dialectic because the divine double is
exactly that it's divine because it's
super it's beyond us it's
incomprehensible but it is where it is
it is the destination to which we are
called to which we are harkening hmm
and it here can you bring this kind of
this out of this conversation that John
and I we had I think last time which was
just this sense of you know would be
interesting to think about it in terms
of in this this dialogue list that we're
having and in dialogue that like is it
possible that we can maybe look at the
part of what that what gives the
dialogue is the realization that the
divine double of the of the of the
dialogue itself yes yes yes I remember
that guy
and a great point yes yes yes thank you
for bringing that in the divine double
of the dialogue itself yes yes yes yeah
I think that yes that's right
and then oh yeah totally and the thing
is you know you
I experienced a bit of that in the
circling that I've done and I'm when I'm
reading other people and reading their
reports they often report something like
that I think that's a very relevant
thing and I think that's there's
indicate there seems to be indications
of something like that all through
plato's work there's often a sense of a
God being present like at the end of a
write and like it might be Apollo or I
forget which Wichita Logan is is it the
Phaedrus at the end where
he Socrates place to be praised to pan
but there's a sense of a God being
present throughout the dialogue and not
in an intrusive way right you know but
abundant but you know in a in a fashion
like you're describing a guy so I think
that yeah I think there's definitely
that's a really good there's a divine
double to the deal logos itself yes yes
and then that divine devil is sort of a
gothic Lee creative of the potential of
that deal logos it's something like that
yeah yeah it's but again it's the
trouble with us is we've we've have 2000
years of a particular interpretation of
that word creation that's right that
that could could could take us off
course I think because it's not it's not
like the God right you know yeah
creative in a more sort of spontaneous
like again sort of coming back to this
this for a fertility like that kind of
spontaneous that a fluorescing sense of
creation no I wasn't I wasn't actually
saying that you should change a term
what I was saying is we should emphasize
the adjective rather than just a noun
that the egg apik creativity not enough
foreground a noun but really foreground
the framing adjective because I think
that's that's that's more like it
that's I really like I like that sense
of that in here's gives it that back to
that question that is that vulnerability
of the world where I can't quite tell is
it is it the divine double seeing us
into existence or is it for are we
seeing it to an existence a my by which
I see God is the eye by which he sees me
that's that card right yeah kind of like
a like a like a deep inner yeah yeah
exactly and I hadn't picked up on it
before but this does this
we're having is really affording me
sense into a card because I'd always
took that statement to be a very you
know it was very informative it for me
but I'm sensing an aircard state
statement something much more now
because you know we're getting think
about the the I by you know there's that
intimacy there's the reciprocal opening
but there's the vulnerability right
there there there's there's so many of
the notes that we have been saying are
now singing in that statement of that
cart that I didn't hear before like I
understood it to be a strong indication
of her participatory knowing within
Neoplatonism but I wasn't getting all
but you can well I know at least be I
can hear all of what we're saying now in
that card statement there I can hear all
the divine doubling the mutual
vulnerability the disclosure the then
you know the DNR what did you call the
did the D anonymizing right all of that
happening all of that in that in that
phrase yes and and and when and when
this when the D Ilocos functions in this
sacral way the identity of the
conversation the identity of the
conversing is identical to that the
identity of the conversing is identical
to that to that blending of identity I'm
not even sure exactly what I mean by
that but the currency to it occurs to me
that when that you know what I mean but
what we mean by that sort of when when
the dialog becomes an entity unto itself
that the I the way that ident that way
that entity identifies the sort of the
the verse of that identification seems
to blend into the the fee ah the short
of the seeing organ right yeah yeah yeah
yeah no yeah as far as the process by
which it sort of comes into its identity
is also the process by which the
intelligibility of the diello goes is is
coming out you find its identity is
identifying as that yeah yeah I
I'm really getting the senses throughout
the recognition we can have both
positions like innocent as is
probability that's yeah do you mean by
that that sometimes I feel I'm speaking
and sometimes I feel like I'm being
spoken yeah that's what you mean yes
totally totally some point you can
randomly go down your weapon and I can
find myself in one or the other in there
yeah yes something important that maybe
both of them happen and in that they can
happen that is itself its own yes yes
very much yes I agree with that
yeah there's a certain like artfulness
or skillfulness of actually being able
to be in relationship of that feeling in
that sensation so it's moving very
smoothly yes yes
maybe mm-hmm I think of it as a metaphor
I keep coming back to what I think about
this is is is like an electrical
conductor that what it's doing it's it's
conducting something its notches which
is which is which sort of which i think
is commensurate with this idea that it's
not that it's not it's not fabricated or
or contrived but it's also not whole its
we're not wholly being foisted either
that there's some there's a sort of a
meeting but then it has that meeting
quality and and I think that sort of the
connecting metaphor to me kind of speaks
to it because then it also speaks to the
consequent circuitry that you can
cultivate to support the conductor and
it also that's right that's right
because that exact and then if you blend
the two metaphors to blend the two
analogies together I think that's
something yeah that's wonderful that's
really wonderful hi very expanded like
yeah yeah I'm actually founded myself
hoping that somebody who watches this if
it in fact is made available to be
watched is very deeply on profound
strong drugs right now
well if you've gotten this far they are
well this is uh so I'm getting ready
just to get this really interesting kind
of a contrast but I'm getting ready to
work with a couple who are coming to me
because they just said that they want to
get a divorce so having this last
conversation we were having a
conversation to look at what what can be
possible and I just feel like
just from this conversation I just it I
feel completely prepared hmm well I'm
glad to hear you that's very touching
yeah that's great but that but that's
that's again that's the that's what you
see at the end of the Platonic dialogues
there's often no argumentative
resolution but people will say but now I
want my son's to to spend time with
Socrates they people now feel somehow
that they've come into a change that
right but it doesn't mean that they've
come to a definition or an argumentative
conclusion now there's been something
there's been a different kind of
resolution right in a sense of you know
of your vision being resolved rather
than coming to a conclusion they become
by affinity okay I'm gonna walk away
from this a lot more coordinated yeah
well well said well said well said
that's a good way of thinking of it too
about that kind of multi-dimensional
coordination being what comes out of the
operatic dialogues as a political
particularly young yeah yeah yes check
this out check this out
it's funny I think I just feel like
we're actually coming to a natural
closures I'm noticing the things that I
put out in the beginning are now
beginning to tool and so in the process
of this particular conversation a guy
explicitly I think all of us also have
this feeling of coming out of this more
coordinated more capable of coordination
now guys about to enter into a
relationship where his capacity now
being more capable of coordination will
afford a higher degree of coordination
among those with him he's in
relationship which will for sure
having been through a divorce will
afford a at the very least and
amelioration of a degradation of
capacity and may in fact afford a higher
increase of capacity for coordination so
this is that this is that gift right
this is the plenitude this is the thing
by doing it we increase the capacity to
do which increases the capacity to do
which increases the caster to do it on
going late there seems to be no reason
to believe that there would be any end
mmm-hmm I agree with that very well
hardly yeah hmm god yes and it increases
your capacity the now is Chris the one
I'm attaching to Chris to step into that
future so as to most fully make your
your past incomprehensible you know it
gives you the increases your capacity to
step more fully on to that path and it's
walk that straight and narrow path that
that our friends Paul and Jonathan would
tell us was named and long ago yes see
there's always there's always there's
always the benevolent ghosts surrounding
any any any dialog right that's that's
[Laughter]
everybody thank you so much I feel yep
gifted beyond belief yeah yeah I want to
thank everybody to and this was a I'm
glad this was recorded and thank you for
for recording it because it's going to
be extremely beneficial to the project
that I am engaging in the other was just
a law mmm there's a lot of gems and what
happened here today that a lot of stuff
to being connected and put together and
in such a fluid and one of the things I
was really interested about is it seemed
to me like this was example fine what
I'm after where we seem to be moving
between something that has aspects of
circling but also aspects of phyleus
ophea in it where we're discussing you
know what is what is coordination what
is vulnerable there's there's a topic
under discussion but there's also the
circling and there's the implication of
the distributed court like it's it seems
like we were exemplifying exactly what
I'm seeking for yeah so thank you for
that very much wonderful harmony yes do
it at the grocery store like it's like
and at some level I just want to
highlight that it's really we're just
doing something on one level that we do
up all the time anyways the medium that
a fourth can afford this isn't something
that I think yeah yeah I mean what it
what is
lighter than a conversation very
continuously so I feel much better able
to converse thank you well gentlemen I
think we should put a draw to a close
where we're at were literally at the
appointed time and we agreed we would
end and I think Jordan is right
I think he's felt sense that we've come
to a closure it's correct so just thank
everybody and guy are you gonna upload
this to your channel is that what we'll
do yeah I'll give you a link yeah and
then I'll promote it through my network
and you know and I'll probably send a
link to David fuller of rebel wisdom
because I think they'd be very
interested in this too if that's okay
with everybody here yeah okay with me
okay great thank you very much gentlemen
and hopefully we will do this again soon
thank you